<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trip Report on Virtualizing a Physical World</title>
    <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/tags/trip-report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trip Report on Virtualizing a Physical World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.thomgreene.com/tags/trip-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Accomplished: Openstack in a Month</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-08-31-missioncomplete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-08-31-missioncomplete/</guid>
      <description>In July I posted about my insane goal of giving a talk at VMworld on a technology I knew nothing about. I chose Openstack, which at that time was nothing more than a buzzword to me. I remember reading tweets saying VMware Administrators needed to pay attention to Openstack but couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell you what it was.
VMworld has arrived and on Monday, August 29th, 2016 I presented my talk. I am not afraid of public speaking but got some jitters as the crew started counting me down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VCAP6-DCV Deploy Beta Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-06-29-vcap6deploybeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-06-29-vcap6deploybeta/</guid>
      <description>I sat the VCAP6-DCV Beta last night. First off the test was extremely fun, much like the VCAP5-DCA. In a live lab your skills are really tested. The new interface provided some challenges but is overall better than the legacy interface. The console is faster and it&amp;rsquo;s a lot nicer to be able to open the manual over the interface. It is very cramped though. My center maybe had an 18 inch monitor so I was still minimizing my manual a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VCAP5-DCD Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-04-08-vcap5dcdexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-04-08-vcap5dcdexperience/</guid>
      <description>On March 29th I posted about VMware&amp;rsquo;s announcement regarding the retirement of the VCAP5 exams. Passing these exams have always been a bucket list item for me. I feel that they confirm a technician&amp;rsquo;s ability to actually use and conceptualize VMware more beyond the typical multiple choice exam. The VCP has become required for many job so having the next level up should set me apart from the competition.
So after my March 8th pass I started gathering material to sit the DCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VCAP5-DCA Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-03-18-vcap5dcaexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-03-18-vcap5dcaexperience/</guid>
      <description>On March 3, 2016 I set the VCAP5-DCA exam. This was the most stressful and exciting test I had ever taken. Below are my thoughts and experiences on the exam. I originally posted them on the Techexams.net Virtualization Forum
The blueprint is 100% on point for this test. Download it, download a checklist too and check off each point as you are reading and labbing them. I used the pluralsight Optimize and Scale course taught by Jason Nash, I had Staples print and bind the PDF study guide found at https://paulgrevink.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>