<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vrealize Operations Manager on Virtualizing a Physical World</title>
    <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/tags/vrealize-operations-manager/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vrealize Operations Manager on Virtualizing a Physical World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:57:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tbgree00.github.io/tags/vrealize-operations-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vRealize Operations Manager: Licensing and License Groups</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropslicensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropslicensing/</guid>
      <description>Licensing Maintaining valid licensing in vRealize Operations Manager is crucial to getting the most out of the tool.
To begin the discussion on licensing there are two key concepts: the license and the license group.
A license is a key that provides specific features and capabilities to vRealize</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vRealize Operations Manager: Design Introduction</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignintro/</guid>
      <description>Sizing a vRealize Operations Manager Environment VMware vRealize Operations Manager is the flagship monitoring suite for the entire VMware Software Defined Datacenter stack. The software is incredibly powerful, but it can be a bit daunting to a newcomer. Each update has improved out of the box functionality, however there is a lot to learn to master the software and truly make the most out of its features. Every successful environment starts with a strong design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vRealize Operations Manager: Design for a Home Lab</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignlab/</guid>
      <description>Designing for a Home Lab A practical way to gain experience with vRealize Operations Manager is to deploy and implement it into a home lab. A design for a home lab almost seems too simple, but planning it out and diagraming a simple example can help when the time comes to design a production environment. The environment will need to support the following:
 Monitor 100 Objects Monitor 10 End Point Operations Management agents  The environment is also resource constrained, and the node can be no larger than a Small node size.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>