<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtualizing a Physical World</title>
    <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Virtualizing a Physical World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:57:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tbgree00.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vRealize Operations Manager: Licensing and License Groups</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropslicensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropslicensing/</guid>
      <description>Licensing Maintaining valid licensing in vRealize Operations Manager is crucial to getting the most out of the tool.
To begin the discussion on licensing there are two key concepts: the license and the license group.
A license is a key that provides specific features and capabilities to vRealize</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Tech Field Day Delegate, vExpert, VCIX, VCAP, VCP, vDad, Disney Nerd
Thanks for reading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Operations Manager</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/page/vrops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/page/vrops/</guid>
      <description> Design  Introduction to Sizing and Design Designing for a Home Lab Designing for a Medium Environment Licensing vRealize Operations Manager  Videos  vRealize Operations Manager: From Zero to Useful  Resources  VMware Hands on Labs 1801-01-CMP, 1801-02-CMP, 1801-03-CMP, 1801-04-CMP Pluralsight course by David Davis mylearn.vmware.com Learning Paths Official vROPs Documentation Sizing Guide VMware KB2150421  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vRealize Operations Manager: Design Introduction</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignintro/</guid>
      <description>Sizing a vRealize Operations Manager Environment VMware vRealize Operations Manager is the flagship monitoring suite for the entire VMware Software Defined Datacenter stack. The software is incredibly powerful, but it can be a bit daunting to a newcomer. Each update has improved out of the box functionality, however there is a lot to learn to master the software and truly make the most out of its features. Every successful environment starts with a strong design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vRealize Operations Manager: Design for a Home Lab</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vropsdesignlab/</guid>
      <description>Designing for a Home Lab A practical way to gain experience with vRealize Operations Manager is to deploy and implement it into a home lab. A design for a home lab almost seems too simple, but planning it out and diagraming a simple example can help when the time comes to design a production environment. The environment will need to support the following:
 Monitor 100 Objects Monitor 10 End Point Operations Management agents  The environment is also resource constrained, and the node can be no larger than a Small node size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Public Speaking - Mentors to Help you Rock It</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/hackingpublicspeaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/hackingpublicspeaking/</guid>
      <description>Public speaking is hard. Standing in front of a crowd and being the center of attention can be a scary thought. Luckily, there are many members of the technology community out there willing to ease you through it. At VMworld 2017 I was fortunate enough to participate in a vBrownBag panel discussion with some giants in the VMware community: Edward Haletky, Simon Long, and Ariel Sanchez Mora.
The four of us were talking after the session and decided we would like to formally arrange a mentoring program to help give back to the community that has helped us so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2017 is Almost Here</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vmworld2017preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/vmworld2017preview/</guid>
      <description>VMworld 2017 is upon us and looks to be busy as ever. I&amp;rsquo;ll be returning to Las Vegas and the place this ride started last year. There has been a LOT happening in my life during the past 50 weeks. I&amp;rsquo;m proud to say I joined Rackspace in the Specialist Cloud Architecture business, representing VMware products and services. As many of you also know, I joined the vBrownBag crew and will be hanging out at the TechTalk booth as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Azure Storage Account</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurestorageacct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurestorageacct/</guid>
      <description>In my article about creating an Azure virtual machine, I walked us through the very basic wizard to create a VM. There is an entire segment of the virtual machine build process dedicated to optional features. These features allow new virtual machines to integrate a VM into an existing Azure environment. When we created our first machine we accepted the default settings, which created new network and storage accounts. That works perfectly for a first look but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be appropriate for use in a real life Azure Infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting a Misconfigured vSwitch</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/switchmisconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/switchmisconfig/</guid>
      <description>Years ago I received a call for help from someone setting up a vSphere host. The install had never worked right and the clients were upset at the upgrade. It sometimes took 30 seconds to connect to a server and their SQL applications would crash daily. My intuition told me there was something strange going on with the network.
It was a very basic install with one Standard vSwitch doing management and virtual machine network traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Atomic Test and Set for Incompatible Storage Arrays</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/disableats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/disableats/</guid>
      <description>After performing an upgrade from ESXi 4.1/ESXi 5.0 to ESXi 5.5 u2 I noticed increased latency events on hosts. More troubling, the affected hosts were frequently dropping all presented datastores, though they would reconnect within a few seconds. The events may appear in your event log as below:
While there are many possible causes to explore these sorts of connectivity issues, one that is often overlooked is how ESXi heartbeating to the datastores.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>