<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vdm30in30 on Virtualizing a Physical World</title>
    <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/tags/vdm30in30/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vdm30in30 on Virtualizing a Physical World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.thomgreene.com/tags/vdm30in30/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want a Home Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-20-soyouwantahomelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-20-soyouwantahomelab/</guid>
      <description>In 2008 I purchased a Dell T110 tower server for my home. I wanted something to run ESXi 4 on so I could run Windows 2003 servers to study for my MCSE. From that point on a home lab has been critical to my success as a technician. It is very common for a technical professional to have some sort of personal space to mess around with.
There are many reasons someone may want to spend hard earned money on a home lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCenter Plugin Tracker Spreadsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-19-vcenterplugintracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-19-vcenterplugintracker/</guid>
      <description>As vCenter has evolved many programs and plugins depend on it for functionality. With the recent GA to vSphere 6.5 a discussion came up on twitter. Veeam released version 9.5 around the same time but it&amp;rsquo;s not compatible with vSphere 6.5. I tried to install Veeam into my lab but couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Instead I was met with an error warning me to wait until Veeam 9.5 Update 1.
The discussion about Compatibility reminded me of the spreadsheet I use to track plugins and configuration of all my servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vExpert 2017 Applications are Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-08-vexpert2017application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-08-vexpert2017application/</guid>
      <description>The application for vExpert 2017 opened today and go through December 16th. The vExpert program is a VMware advocacy group that recognizes people who give back to the VMware community and promote VMware technology. You can become a vExpert by leading a VMUG, speaking, blogging, and/or tweeting your support of VMware technology.
I can say one of the best things that has happened in my career was being selected as vExpert 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps for my VCDX Design</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-06-vcdxfirststeps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-06-vcdxfirststeps/</guid>
      <description>I have publicly committed to submitting a design to the VCDX committee. My design is due in March 2017. I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I signed up to submit because it has kick started my motivation. Today I wanted to talk about my progress.
I am using an actual design for a project I worked on. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly complex system with many moving pieces. It mostly meets AMPRS requirements (Availability, Manageability, Performance, Recoverability, Security) so I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to do much tweaking to make it pass muster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You be a Full Stack Engineer</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-05-fullstackengineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-05-fullstackengineer/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the Full Stack Journey podcast. In the show Scott Lowe investigates the question &amp;ldquo;Can someone truly be a full stack engineer?”. He and his guests work together to give actionable advice and talk about the benefits of being a full stack engineer vs working in a silo.
The definition of a full stack engineer really hard to pin down. Many people have opinions on the matter and they revolve around some common themes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Would I Advise Someone to Avoid in their Career?</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-03-advicetoavoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-03-advicetoavoid/</guid>
      <description>I am a regular listener to The Geek Whisperers podcast. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t listened to them before please check them out here. Trust me, you won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. The podcast always has a very interesting guest and they talk soft skills and high level concepts with very technical people. A lot of their discussion revolves around career paths, decisions that lead their guest to their current position, and practical advice a listener can implement to change, improve, or develop similar skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Steps for my VCDX Design</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-01-vdm30in30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-11-01-vdm30in30/</guid>
      <description>After a lot of going back and fourth, gnashing my teeth, etc I decided to participate in the #vDM30in30 challenge. I suppose that starting a VCDX design and working to improve my presentation skills wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Add on work responsibilities and family time and I have a challenge ahead of me.
I refuse to let doubt or fear stop me so here I go. In the next month I hope to talk about the following topics (and more!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>