<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Virtualizing a Physical World</title>
    <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Virtualizing a Physical World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:57:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Azure Storage Account</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2017/6/3/how-to-create-an-azure-storage-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2017/6/3/how-to-create-an-azure-storage-account/</guid>
      <description>In my article about creating an Azure virtual machine, I walked us through the very basic wizard to create a VM. There is an entire segment of the virtual machine build process dedicated to optional features. These features allow new virtual machines to integrate a VM into an existing Azure environment. When we created our first machine we accepted the default settings, which created new network and storage accounts. That works perfectly for a first look but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be appropriate for use in a real life Azure Infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging SSO Domains in vCenter Server 5.5 pt 2: How?</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/11/7/merging-sso-domains-in-vcenter-server-55-pt-2-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/11/7/merging-sso-domains-in-vcenter-server-55-pt-2-how/</guid>
      <description>In part 1 of my discussion about Merging SSO Domains I discussed why I was required to make that change. To recap: Enhanced Linked Mode is a business requirement in 6.0 and that requires all vCenters to belong to the same SSO Domain. You can&amp;rsquo;t merge SSO domains in 6.0 so we need to do it before the upgrade.
While the concept sounds simple enough execution gets a bit complicated. There are a lot of services that need to be modified and some architectural decisions to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging SSO Domains in vCenter 5.5 part 1: Why?</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/11/4/merging-sso-domains-in-vcenter-55-part-1-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/11/4/merging-sso-domains-in-vcenter-55-part-1-why/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes tasks that seem simple at first can become very complicated. When I was first tasked with upgrading a vCenter 5.5 environment to 6.0 I imagined mounting an ISO, clicking through the wizard, and voila, upgrade complete. This may work when you only have one vCenter server in a simple environment, however in an enterprise this is typically far from the optimal way to approach the upgrade.
Over the next couple of entries I will talk about my progress toward a vSphere 6 upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Going into the VCAP6-DCV Deploy</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/6/25/strategy-going-into-the-vcap6-dcv-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/6/25/strategy-going-into-the-vcap6-dcv-deploy/</guid>
      <description>As I prepare to take an advanced test on a version of VMware I had never touched prior to dropping my $100 I knew I needed a strategy. I searched the blueprint for what was new and hoped my notes from the DCA were enough to patch me through.
Plenty of articles exist to study by. I used many of them to prepare myself. When the time comes for me to take my seat here is how I&amp;rsquo;ll prepare:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCAP6-DCV Deploy Blueprint Changes from VCAP5-DCA</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/6/16/vcap6-dcv-deploy-blueprint-changes-from-vcap5-dca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/6/16/vcap6-dcv-deploy-blueprint-changes-from-vcap5-dca/</guid>
      <description>VMware recently announced a 2 week availability for the VCAP6-DCV Deploy beta. After some debate I signed up to sit the exam on June 28, 2016. They provide a beta version of the blueprint so I started there to see what had changed from my VCAP5-DCA 5.5 blueprint and notes. I made some quick notes and want to share them here.
 As a disclaimer my list is quick first pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating VM Configuration Changes</title>
      <link>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/3/11/x3s639ch7peru7quudjenlbcb9vhw0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thomgreene.com/blog/2016/3/11/x3s639ch7peru7quudjenlbcb9vhw0/</guid>
      <description>Tracking resource configuration is a common struggle for an enterprise level environment. Even SMBs can have trouble keeping track of how their memory is provisioned and when it changes. What&amp;rsquo;s worse, VMware&amp;rsquo;s vSphere Client doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any insight as to what changes when someone edits the virtual machine settings. An event named &amp;ldquo;Reconfigure virtual machine&amp;rdquo; hits the task log but this isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of information. If you open Edit Settings and click OK vCenter registers this event even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t change anything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>