<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Virtualizing a Physical World</title>
    <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/categories/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Virtualizing a Physical World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:57:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tbgree00.github.io/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Azure Storage Account</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurestorageacct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurestorageacct/</guid>
      <description>In my article about creating an Azure virtual machine, I walked us through the very basic wizard to create a VM. There is an entire segment of the virtual machine build process dedicated to optional features. These features allow new virtual machines to integrate a VM into an existing Azure environment. When we created our first machine we accepted the default settings, which created new network and storage accounts. That works perfectly for a first look but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be appropriate for use in a real life Azure Infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Azure Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurevm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurevm/</guid>
      <description>One of the most basic tasks a VMware administrator will perform is deploying a virtual machine. Whether it is creating a VM from scratch or using a template, we&amp;rsquo;ve all worked through the wizard.
As I dig deeper into Azure I can&amp;rsquo;t help but bring my experience with vSphere along with me. The Azure Resource Manger is a very different experience from the vSphere Web Client but there also quite a few similarities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Azure for Free</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurefree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/azurefree/</guid>
      <description>I recently created a blog post about Getting Started with AWS. I like what they do and think they&amp;rsquo;re a great platform but there is more than one horse in the public cloud race. Microsoft Azure is a close second to AWS and getting better every day. Microsoft has many advantages that AWS doesn&amp;rsquo;t: They are probably already in your datacenter and you probably have an ELA with them. If you do, check and see if there are Azure credits in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis the Season for Certification</title>
      <link>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/tistheseason2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tbgree00.github.io/post/tistheseason2016/</guid>
      <description>The end of the calendar year brings family, travel, and performance evaluations. A big part of mine is training and tech development. It&amp;rsquo;s never too soon to start thinking about what is new and where your are interested in strengthening your skill.
I asked some tech experts what skills are the stuff to learn for 2017. Keith Townsend @ctoadvisor responded with
 Scripting (ie Cloud Formation, Powershell, Python)
Hybrid infrastructure networking (AWS VPC&amp;gt;VPN integration)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>