<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on thomgreene.com</title>
    <link>https://thomgreene.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on thomgreene.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 12:39:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thomgreene.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>At-Home Certification: The New Normal</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-05-25-onlinecertification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 12:39:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-05-25-onlinecertification/</guid>
      <description>2020 will go down in history as the year that changed the world. A global pandemic forced everyone to stay indoors, employers were forced to embrace work-from-home, and companies that supported employees had to respond. One industry that responded quickly was certification. Pearson Vue had already allowed some certification to be taken at home, but now most major technology vendors got on board. This opens up a new world of opportunity and a degree of accessibility that benefits everyone in the IT industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Azure Storage Account</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2017/2017-06-03-azurestorageacct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2017/2017-06-03-azurestorageacct/</guid>
      <description>In my article about creating an Azure virtual machine, I walked us through the very basic wizard to create a VM. There is an entire segment of the virtual machine build process dedicated to optional features. These features allow new virtual machines to integrate a VM into an existing Azure environment. When we created our first machine we accepted the default settings, which created new network and storage accounts. That works perfectly for a first look but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be appropriate for use in a real life Azure Infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Azure Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2017/2017-05-30-azurevm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2017/2017-05-30-azurevm/</guid>
      <description>One of the most basic tasks a VMware administrator will perform is deploying a virtual machine. Whether it is creating a VM from scratch or using a template, we&amp;rsquo;ve all worked through the wizard.
As I dig deeper into Azure I can&amp;rsquo;t help but bring my experience with vSphere along with me. The Azure Resource Manger is a very different experience from the vSphere Web Client but there also quite a few similarities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Azure for Free</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2017/2017-05-26-azurefree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2017/2017-05-26-azurefree/</guid>
      <description>I recently created a blog post about Getting Started with AWS. I like what they do and think they&amp;rsquo;re a great platform but there is more than one horse in the public cloud race. Microsoft Azure is a close second to AWS and getting better every day. Microsoft has many advantages that AWS doesn&amp;rsquo;t: They are probably already in your datacenter and you probably have an ELA with them. If you do, check and see if there are Azure credits in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud = Outsourcing</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-06-10-cloudoutsourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-06-10-cloudoutsourcing/</guid>
      <description>Discussion of the cloud seems to be popping up around me daily. Part of it is my own instigation but other people are starting the discussions as well. It is always a lively debate with three sides. There&amp;rsquo;s very pro-cloud, cloud for specific use cases, and there are the totally anti-cloud people. A member of that political faction contributed the following quote to the meeting&amp;rsquo;s chat:
 Cloud n. /Kloud/ def.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Head has been in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-05-20-headincloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 12:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2016/2016-05-20-headincloud/</guid>
      <description>About two years ago I just happened to read an article in CIO magazine about &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of virtualization and getting the most computing for my money. Reading about AWS in particular really excited me. I thought of Amazon as a fantastic retailer and this article and the research done afterward really opened my eyes.
I&amp;rsquo;m all about infrastructure and approached my studies from that perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>