<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Thom Talks Tech</title>
    <link>https://thomgreene.com/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Thom Talks Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 14:09:23 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thomgreene.com/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Converting Windows Server 2019 Evaluation Licensing to Volume Licensing</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-07-16-windows-server-licensing-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 14:09:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-07-16-windows-server-licensing-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft provides evaluation version of Windows Server 2019 on their website. These are intended to allow users to deploy a temporary server for testing or checking out new features. It isn&amp;rsquo;t an easy feat to convert these into KMS servers. In a recent lab environment we used the Windows Server 2019 evaluation without understanding the difficulty in converting it to NFR once we received those licenses. We researched the problem and found a solution to convert a server created with an evaluation ISO to a KMS licensed lab VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Fundamentals Exam Experience</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-05-26-azurefundamental/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:09:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-05-26-azurefundamental/</guid>
      <description>The Microsoft Azure Fundamentals certification (AZ-900) is an entry-level exam, introducing Azure to technical and non-technical people. The test covers a range of general cloud concepts and Microsoft products. This exam gives students a firm foundation to continue learning Microsoft Azure and to participate in the infrastructure shift from on-premises to the cloud.
The Azure Fundamentals exam is about 35 questions with a 60-minute time limit. They are a mix of drop-down, drag and drop, and multiple-choice questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At-Home Certification: The New Normal</title>
      <link>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-05-25-onlinecertification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 12:39:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomgreene.com/post/2020/2020-05-25-onlinecertification/</guid>
      <description>2020 will go down in history as the year that changed the world. A global pandemic forced everyone to stay indoors, employers were forced to embrace work-from-home, and companies that supported employees had to respond. One industry that responded quickly was certification. Pearson Vue had already allowed some certification to be taken at home, but now most major technology vendors got on board. This opens up a new world of opportunity and a degree of accessibility that benefits everyone in the IT industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
